And then there's no greater privilege in the world than doing ministry with strangers who
become friends and friends who become family.
And so when we talked about doing Sabbath, I just knew that Brian had to come share with
us about kind of his journey in this process and what Sabbath has taught him and his family.
I have learned so much from you, not just about Sabbath, but about the Lord and his goodness.
And not just through the things that you've taught me with your mouth, but the example
that you've lived with your life.
And so just wanted all of you to know, if you haven't met Brian yet, this is Brian.
He's been a part of our family, our church family since it started.
And he has wisdom from God to share with us.
So thanks.
Thank you.
Maybe this is always the awkward time when like, I don't know if my microphone's on or
not.
Is it going?
We're good.
We're, we got a, we got a hot mic.
That's awesome.
Hey, good morning, everybody.
Thank you guys for making time to be here this morning.
It has been a weird week, right?
I know for me and I know for me and my family, it's been hard to get up and, and moving in
the mornings, but, uh, uh, but I'm glad that you guys are here this morning.
And I think that God has something that he wants to share with us today.
Um, like pastor Ryan, uh, talked about, I am not a preacher.
Um, and public speaking is not typically in my, uh, in my wheelhouse here, but, um, but he
asked me to come and speak with you guys today because this practice of Sabbath is something
that me and my family have been doing for the last three or four years.
It's been really formative in the way that we shape our lives, not just, um, the, the
24 or 36 hours that we devote Sabbath itself, but the way that we approach the week and our
posture towards the world, uh, that we interact with.
So, um, so I guess that's why I'm here.
I don't know.
Um, if you're new to us, we're in, we're in the middle of a three year series about different
spiritual practices that we might be able to develop to, um, to approach the world more
like Jesus did.
These are, um, spiritual practices that we're in.
Um, and we're in a four week series on Sabbath.
This is week number three.
Um, today we're going to talk about, um, the delight that we experienced during Sabbath and
the work that God can do in us through that.
Um, so the plan today, we'll, we'll read some Scripture.
We'll talk about Scripture a little bit, and then hopefully give you guys some practical
tips of how you could, might start interacting with this practice in your family, um, and in
your lives.
So let's pray and then we'll get started.
Holy God, creator of the universe, we love you.
We thank you that you say that we are created in your image to bear your image to a world that
needs to see it.
We know that your spirit's here with us.
We know that your spirit is, is in us, and we thank you for that.
We pray that you would bless our time today.
You would speak to our hearts and speak to our minds.
And that as we, um, learn more about the time that you set aside for us to be with you,
you would change us through that.
It's in Jesus' name that we pray, amen.
All right, so I want to start in one of my favorite Scriptures of the Bible.
We're going to start back at the very beginning of the Bible in Genesis 1.
Um, and if you're new to Christianity or haven't been around it much, this is the part of the
Bible where God lays out how the earth was created and the heavens and all these things
that we interact with on a daily basis.
And so the first verse of the Bible starts out like this.
It's this summary statement of, in the beginning, God created the heavens and the earth.
And then it goes through six days of, of detailing how that happens.
And it's this beautiful, um, ancient nearest Eastern poem with this, with this rhythm.
It has this rhythm to it.
And we don't have time to parse out all that stuff today.
I would love to with you guys at some point.
It's pretty awesome.
Um, but, uh, I want to pick out a couple pieces of it because I think it's pertinent to what
we're talking about today.
So for the sake of time, we won't talk about all six days of this, uh, of creation in this
poem, but I do want to read the first day, um, of creation as an example.
It says, and God said, let there be light.
And there was light.
God saw the light was good.
The word there, good in Hebrew is tov.
It's this idea that, um, something's beautiful or pleasant.
God saw the light and the light was good.
And he separated the light from the darkness.
God called the light day and the darkness, he called night.
And there was evening and there was morning the first day.
And every day of creation goes on like this, that God creates and then he says it's good.
And then there's evening and morning the next day.
God creates the light.
He says, it's good.
There's evening and morning.
He creates land and sea and he says it's good.
And there's evening and there's morning.
He creates plants on the surface of the earth and he calls them good.
And there's evening and morning.
He creates lights in the sky, the sun and the stars and the moon.
He says that they're good.
There's evening and morning.
He creates fish and birds and he blesses them.
And he goes, he says, fill up the sea and fill up the sky.
And he says, you're good.
And there's evening and morning.
He creates creatures on the land and humans and he blesses them.
And he says, fill it up.
And he says, you're good.
And there's evening and morning.
There's this rhythm God creates.
He says, it's good.
There's evening.
And then there's morning.
And then we get to verse 31 and it says this, God saw all that he had made and it was very
good.
The Hebrew there is tov mayod.
They don't have the idea of necessarily perfection like we have it, but it's this idea that nature
is complete, that the world that he has created has everything that it needs to keep going.
There's nothing that it's missing.
And he said, it's very good.
It's tov mayod.
God saw all that he made and it was very good.
And there was evening and there was morning, the sixth day, thus the heavens and the earth
were completed in all their vast array.
And by the seventh day, God had finished the work that he'd been doing.
So on the seventh day, he rested from all of his work and God blessed the seventh day and
made it holy because on it, he rested from the work of creating that he had done.
And this is our first look at Sabbath, right?
God works and he says it's good and then he rests.
And later on in the story, we're told that we're created in the image of this God.
And what we know of God to this point is this rhythm, right?
He creates, he says it's good and he rests.
And obviously later on in the story, sin enters the world and this spirals and the pain and sin
is introduced into the world.
But even when God decides to wipe it clean through a flood, he preserves his goodness and
the ark with Noah and the animals.
And when he lands them safely, he puts this good back into the world and he says, fill it up,
you're blessed.
And there's not a time that I can recall in Scripture where God turns away from his posture
of goodness towards the world, right?
And so we're created in the image of this God that still holds his posture towards the world
that it's good, it's full of goodness.
But this, it's hard to see, right?
You know, it's not hard to find pain and it's not hard to find the bad things in the world.
So how in the world do we as Christians lay hold of our identity as image bearers of a God
who sees the world as good?
I think Jesus has some wisdom for us, as he usually does.
Let's go to Matthew chapter six together.
This is in the middle of Jesus' Sermon on the Mount.
If you're not familiar with this teaching, this is the largest teaching that Jesus gives
at one time in his ministry.
It's like his greatest hits.
It's pretty awesome.
And so in the middle of this sermon that Jesus gives, he hits this part that says, lay up for
yourselves treasures in heaven.
Don't lay up for yourselves treasures on earth.
And the idea behind that is that don't spend your time working for things that are going
to perish anyway.
Don't exhaust yourselves accumulating things that are going to go away, but spend your time
focusing on things that have eternal ramifications, namely loving God and loving the people around
you, right?
And so then we hit this verse that goes like this.
The eye is the lamp of the body.
If your eyes are good, your whole body will be full of light.
But if your eyes are bad, your whole body will be full of darkness.
If the light within you is darkness, how great is that darkness?
To which we all respond, what in the world are you talking about?
Right?
This hits us as being a little bit weird, right?
But at the time that Jesus gave this teaching, this wouldn't have been considered a weird teaching
or this obscure teaching.
This was a known kind of thought process at the time.
It's the idea of having a good eye versus a bad eye.
The Hebrew for this would be an ayin tovah, an eye that's oriented towards good, or an ayin ra'ah
is the inverse of that.
It's an eye that's oriented towards bad.
And so a person with a good eye will see other people as those that bear the image of God
and will understand that we live in a world that has enough, that it's an abundant world,
that there's enough to go around so we can live with generosity and we can live with open hands
and we can live with hope and joy.
And on the other side, there's this idea of a bad eye, an ayin ra'ah, and somebody that
has this view towards life sees the world as a dog-eat-dog place, like the natural bent
is towards the negative, that there's only so much resource to go around, and so I have
to do everything that I can to collect everything that I want and need.
And humans aren't an image bearer of God.
They're an obstacle that gets in my way as I try and accumulate the things that I want
or need, right?
So when Jesus says, the eye is the lamp of the body, if your eyes are good, your whole
body will be full of light, what he's saying is, if you turn your gaze towards knowing that
there's enough in the world and that you know who your heavenly father is and he takes care
of you, your whole body is going to be full of light and the people around you are going
to see that, right?
But if your eyes are bad and you look towards the negative and you think that there's not
enough to go around and you have to fight for everything that you get, how great is that
darkness, he says.
Right?
We do this with our kids.
It's a gratitude practice.
It's really cute.
We've got twins that are eight.
And so when we lay them down in bed at night, we say, give us an ayin tovah from the day.
And, you know, they're eight, so they say all kinds of weird stuff.
Ayin tovah that my brother's feet weren't smelly today.
You know, that kind of thing.
But then they'll hit the spot and they'll just say beautiful things.
Ayin tovah that I have a family that loves me.
And ayin tovah that we got to eat three meals today.
Right?
And this doesn't mean, this isn't like, this isn't pathologic optimism to have a good eye.
We don't turn our eyes away from the things that are bad in the world.
But we start from a place where we see the good in other people.
And then we can engage those areas of darkness and bring some hope and peace into them.
Right?
So, the next part of the Scripture, it goes on in the Sermon on the Mount.
And Jesus begins to talk about not worrying, which I think is beautiful here.
He says, don't worry about your life, what you'll eat or drink, or about your body, what you're going to wear.
Life's more important than food.
The body's more important than clothes.
Look at flowers.
They don't worry.
They don't work.
But nobody's dressed like those.
Right?
And look at birds.
They don't worry about what their next meal is going to be, what they're going to eat.
But God continues to feed them.
And aren't you more important than birds and flowers?
Your heavenly Father knows you, and he's going to take care of you.
And I know in our congregation that we've got people who live in abundance and that have everything that they need and more.
And I also know that we have people in our congregation that legitimately don't know what their next meal is going to be or how they're going to pay their next rent.
And I don't, what I will tell you is that I know our heavenly Father.
And I know that he knows you and that he loves you.
And he's going to give you everything that you need.
And it probably won't look like the way that you want it to.
And you might not get what you want, but he knows you.
There is enough, and he will take care of you.
So what does this have to do with Sabbath?
Great question.
I was wondering that myself.
God created this, and he knows that left to our own devices that our natural instinct is to turn our gaze towards the negative.
The statistics that I was reading on this say that we have negative thoughts 70 to 80% of the time.
Like that's our natural bent toward life.
And so God sets up this time of Sabbath and puts boundaries around it and says,
this is your time to take your thoughts captive and to turn them towards good things, right?
This is the reason that we delight on Sabbath.
On Sabbath, we make intentional choices to see the good world that God has put us in,
knowing that he gives us everything that we need.
So for the last couple minutes of the time here today, I want to give some practical tips to this.
I told you guys that my family and I started this three or four years ago,
and it's been interesting sorting out what it looks like in our lives, right?
But I think there are some things that are applicable across the board here,
that if we can do some of these, it might help you make some space in your life.
So Brian's practical tips on Sabbath.
Make a list, take some time during the wake.
Make a list of things that you will do on Sabbath and that you won't do on Sabbath, right?
So this might look like on Sabbath, I will take a nap.
On Sabbath, I will eat dessert.
Come on.
Somebody in the back.
Awesome.
Make a list of things that bring you joy and that speak to your soul,
that draw you closer to your creator.
Make a list of I will not.
I will not do my typical work.
I will not do chores that don't bring me joy.
Those kind of things, right?
Make preparations.
We screwed this up so bad when we first started practicing Sabbath.
We really like to dive in with both feet here.
So we decided that we were going to keep traditional Hebrew Sabbath,
meaning that we were going to start at 20 minutes to sundown on Friday
and that we were going to carry it through until Saturday evening.
And so my wife and I both work full time.
We've got kids that are in school.
And so what this looked like in our house is that we would rush in from a busy week at work.
We'd throw some food on the table.
We'd put my kids to bed.
And then my wife and I would look around the disaster of our home and tap our foot
and wonder when we could get about the business of putting our life back together.
And it was awful.
So, like, don't do that.
Now, we've scooted our Sabbath to Saturday evening to Sunday evening.
And we spend the entirety of Saturday preparing for the following day so that we can actually enjoy it.
So take some time and prepare your day.
The next thing that I would say is find some ways to mark the days, put some boundaries around it,
and be intentional about doing things to say, now is when our Sabbath time starts and now is when our Sabbath time ends.
We want to devote this time to God.
And so we mark the ends of it.
This could be singing a song.
This could be saying a prayer.
This could be lighting candles.
That's what we do in our home.
But make sure that we're very intentional about putting these boundaries around the day.
So we've got marking the day to put boundaries around it.
We've got this list of I wills and I won'ts while we're in the day.
And then the next thing that I would say is take some time and intentionally put away worry.
There's this practice that I've heard people talk about with this, something called a Sabbath box,
which I think is a cool idea.
We don't do it, but I think it's a great idea.
The idea here is that you take some time, you write down the things that you're anxious about
or the things that you're worried about.
You put them in a box along with probably your electronic devices, and then you put it away.
So we're symbolically and very practically separating ourselves from the worries that we have.
And then do the things that bring you joy.
And the list here is long.
Take a nap.
Eat dessert.
Take a hike.
Play games with your family.
Sing.
Dance.
Draw.
Do the things that draw you closer to God that make your spirit feel alive.
There's a tendency to think that Sabbath is a day where you sit around and don't do anything.
That's not what it looks like in our house.
I mean, we're very active on Sabbath, but we're active doing the things that bring us to light
and that draw us closer to God.
This is the idea, right?
The other thing that I would say is while you're doing these things, take your time with them.
I do a lot of things throughout the week that should bring me joy but don't because I rush through them.
Like, I'll eat this beautiful meal, but I always eat like I'm at boot camp and I don't really taste the food that I'm eating, right?
And so, on Sabbath, chew your food, right?
It's great, right?
When you go out and take a walk, pick up one of those maple leaves and throw it up in the air and see that thing spiral down and say,
what a creative God we serve.
Like, take your time on the day and enjoy the things that God gives you.
And then be mindful of the work that God's doing in your heart and in your soul as you do all these things.
He's going to do some work on you.
As I was preparing for today, I was thinking about if I wanted to use our family as a case study, which, you know, here we go.
But I thought I'd talk you through what, you know, the 48 hours around Sabbath actually looks like for us
because, like I said, it's hard to see how it might work in your own space.
And this is how we've settled into it.
It's probably going to look different in five years for us.
But this is how it looks for right now.
We get up on Saturday morning and we tidy up any loose ends from work that we have from the last week.
We grocery shop.
We clean our house and do our laundry.
And then we prepare for our meal.
Like, this is our Saturday.
And then on Saturday night, we've had the same, roughly the same group of people coming over to our house for the last several years.
We share a meal with them every Saturday.
And so when everybody comes into the house, we sit at our table and we take a couple minutes to be quiet and to breathe and to put worry away.
And then we light two candles.
One candle represents God's command to us to remember the Sabbath.
And then the other command to set it apart or make it holy.
And when we do this, we say traditional Hebrew prayers for Sabbath in Hebrew.
And it's super weird and awkward for people who haven't been at our house before.
And I'll warn them.
I'm like, it's about to get weird.
And then it does.
And the point of it isn't just to appropriate another culture, which, you know.
But the point is to make it strange enough for my kids that they know that what's happening for the next 24 hours is different than what we do any other time in the week.
Right?
So we want to mark this day.
And so we do strange stuff to do it.
We light our two candles.
And then we hold up our drinks and we say another Hebrew prayer and we thank God for the fruit of the vine, understanding that it comes from him.
And then we hold up our food and we say, thank you, God, for bringing forth bread from the earth, that whatever we do with our hands doesn't matter if it's not blessed by God.
He brings the blessing.
And then we light a candle for each of my children and we bless them.
And we say, Ezra, may God make you like Ephraim and Manasseh and Eliza, may God make you like Sarah, Rebecca, Rachel, and Leah.
And then we eat and we enjoy each other's company.
And what I know is that Sabbath by yourself is pretty great, but Sabbath in community is a lot better.
Right?
So I would encourage you as you're finding times to implement this, find some people to do it with.
It's a lot better.
And we eat dessert.
And my kids, if you ask them why we eat dessert on Sabbath, they'll say, because God's love is sweet.
Right?
It's this hook to remind us that God gives us good things and that he loves us.
And then we go to bed.
We come here the next day, worship with you people.
And then we go home and we take naps and we play games and we read books and we delight.
And then on Sunday night, we make a very simple meal.
Usually, it's sheet pan nachos, which we've affectionately started calling chabachos.
So we eat our chabachos and we watch a movie and that's how we finish our day.
Right?
This is our Sabbath.
So again, it's going to look different for you and for your family and for your time.
But I would encourage you guys to flesh it out and try this practice because God does work through it.
David, you want to come up and play the piano?
I've been looking forward to this part.
Mostly because I love hearing David play the piano.
But like it always sounds so cool when preachers talk with the piano behind them.
Preacher stance.
So church, the idea behind Sabbath is not just to set aside time to rest or relax,
but to set aside, oh man, that's good.
Yeah.
Yeah, keep it going.
Oh man, this is great.
Everything I dreamed.
The goal is to reorient our gaze towards a God that loves us and to turn our eyes towards goodness.
And as I was preparing for today's sermon, it struck me again how countercultural this actually is.
That not just setting aside a day to rest, but to set aside a time to orient ourselves towards the goodness in the world and to see the goodness in the world.
Because what I know about the world is that that's not the posture that the world takes towards itself.
And Jesus calls us to be different than the world.
And I'm afraid that we've misinterpreted that over time.
To say our job as Christians is to smash the world into a mold of Christian morality that they haven't accepted as true yet.
And that leaves us at a spot of being frustrated because why can't the non-believers just stop sinning?
And it leads the world to look at us and say, what a bunch of angry hypocrites.
But guys, if we can lay hold of this practice and if we can take this entire day to reorient our gaze and to turn our eyes to the goodness towards the world.
And to recognize that we serve a God and to recognize that we serve a God and we're created in the image of a God who gives us everything that we need.
Then when it's time to re-engage in a world, we can do it with some hope and we can do it with some joy.
And maybe that's the way that we're counter-cultural, right?
I think as Christians, if we can take this posture that God gives us towards the goodness in the world.
That when we walk into a room, everybody should be able to breathe a little deeper.
And that when we engage in important conversations about important topics, that we can do it with an attitude that brings some hope to it.
And so this is my prayer for you, church.
May the God who created the universe and called it good.
May you be an image bearer of Him as you go throughout your week this week.
May you turn your eyes towards good.
And as you turn your eyes towards good, may that fill up your body with light so that when we engage the darkness, we shed light on it.
May God be glorified with that.
May you rest in knowing who you are and who God is.
In Jesus' name, amen.
I'm about to give Brian the biggest compliment
I've ever given anybody,
which is, Brian, as you were talking,
you reminded me of a Bluey episode.
This is the season of pastoral ministry
you all find yourselves in underneath my leadership.
There's an episode of Bluey called Born Yesterday.
And Bandit, the dad, spends all day with his kids
pretending like he was born yesterday
and asking them all of the questions
about all of the things that he doesn't know about.
And at the end of the episode,
they kind of finish playing the game
and the mom looks out the window
and the dad is sitting on the ground,
cross-legged, staring at a butterfly.
Like it was the first time he's ever seen it before.
And she says, kids,
is your dad still playing Born Yesterday?
And they say, no.
And she looks out at him and just gives like a, hmm.
And as Brian was talking,
I just couldn't help but think that
Sabbath is that opportunity
for us to refresh our eyes
on the goodness of life.
There's so many things that we breeze by
every single day
because of the difficulties and challenges
and anxieties and worries.
There's so many gifts from God
that we walk past, run past, fly past.
And Sabbath is this invitation
to just take a day every week
and to set aside the burdens
and the worries and the anxieties
and just believe that this world is good
and that our God is good
and that he's gonna take care of us.
And what might that change
how we look at everything else?
And so I was just, Brian,
so encouraged by that
and challenged by it.
Part of the reason I'm having such a bad day
is my pipes have been frozen
for like 36 hours.
And again, there's a way to look at that
that turns the eye towards darkness.
And there's a way to look at that
that says my most inconvenient situation
is luxury across half of the world.
And Sabbath is this thing
that postures us towards seeing the good,
delighting in the gifts that God gives us.
So I know it's counter-cultural.
I know it seems so far away for so many of us,
but I hope that a testimony
from two full-time parents
with twin eight-year-olds
figuring out how to receive this invitation from God
might be an encouragement to you
in whatever season you find yourself in.
We're gonna end.
It is so good talking with the piano behind you,
I gotta tell you.
And you're really good at it, Dave.
We're gonna end by taking communion
and this whole service
has kind of had me meditating on
the spiritual reality
that is written by the elder John
in the book of Revelation,
chapters four and five.
And it's become my favorite chapter
in all of Scripture chapters.
And as we've just been talking
about reframing things,
seeing things from a different perspective,
I just think about the passage
where the angel is talking to John
and John hears something
that sounds like a lion,
like the Lion of Judah.
He hears the Lion of Judah.
They're talking about who can open the scroll,
who is worthy to redeem
the goodness of the world.
All of us are broken.
We've all fallen short.
Who is worthy to redeem
God's good creation?
Who is worthy to open up the seal
and to roll out the scroll
of God's redemption plan?
Who is worthy to do it?
And there's weeping
because John thinks
there's nobody who's worthy to do it.
And he hears this Lion of Judah,
this powerful voice,
this roar,
and he turns his head.
And what he sees
sees is not a lion,
but he sees a,
the Greek literally says
a little lamb
as if it were slain.
And all of heaven breaks out
in this praise
that he is worthy,
that the lamb is worthy
to open the seal,
to break open the scroll.
And this is what communion
is for us.
It's this reorientation
about what victory is.
about what success,
what the good life is
because we think about
the good life
as the roaring lion
is going to come in
and save us.
He's going to give us
everything that we need.
He has the power.
He has the capability.
He has it all.
In the kingdom of heaven,
actually,
victory comes through sacrifice.
That the thing
that makes Jesus worthy
is his sacrificial love.
That he came down from heaven,
that he stepped down
from a place of power
and authority
and walked the dust
of the earth.
And the invitation for us
in communion
is to remember
that to be citizens
of the kingdom of heaven
is to walk in victory,
but it is a victory
that comes through
sacrificial love.
It's a reorientation
about what success looks like.
And that is why
it was so weird
when Jesus told his followers,
you're going to eat my flesh
and drink my blood.
It's still weird.
It's not a thing
that we're like,
oh yeah,
not weird anymore.
It's not a thing
that you're going to invite
your friends and say,
guys,
we're going to sit around
the table
and eat the flesh of Christ
and drink his blood.
And they're going to be like,
yeah, that's normal.
Let's do it.
It's still weird.
But the thing
that makes it not weird
is when we allow it
to reframe our vision
for what life
is truly about.
So I invite you
if you're a follower of Jesus
to take Christ's body
broken for you.
Christ's blood
shed for you.
Hey, Bri,
we didn't talk about this.
You don't have to do
the Hebrew version.
Do you want to end
in the kind of culmination
Sabbath prayer for us?
You don't have to do
the Hebrew version.
You can just do the English.
If you want to be weird.
I won't subject you
to my Hebrew,
but if you see my kids,
ask them to do it
because hearing an eight-year-old
speak Hebrew
is pretty great.
So the prayer that we say
as we start Sabbath
is in English.
It says,
Blessed are you,
eternal our God,
sovereign of time
and space.
You hallow us
with your mitzvah,
meaning that you set us apart
with your commands
and you command us
to kindle the lights
of Shabbat.
So that's our intro prayer.
Go in peace, church.
I was really hoping
he'd do the Hebrew.
We will have volunteers
at the prayer tent.
If you have had a rough week
like me
and need someone
to pray over you,
please come see us.
We'd love to pray for you.
Lord, my God, mercy,
I give you control.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
You hurt me.
I was feeling empty.
Lord, my God, mercy,
I give you control.
Because you brought me
out to bring you.
So we've had a way
forever to give you praise.
We thank you.
Pray for better days.
My morning's under praise.
Forever we give you thanks.
We thank you.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
That joy is everlasting.
I cried out into you, Lord, you, Lord, yeah.
And you rescued me.
Refused to love my enemies, enemies, triumph over me.
Heard me, I was feeling empty, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me.
I was feeling empty, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me.
I was feeling empty, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me, Lord, my God.
I gave you control over me, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me, Lord, my God, have mercy, I gave you control over me, Lord, my God.
I gave you control over me, Lord, my God.